{
  "translations": {
    "en": {
      "q2": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "We need to sutdy the closure properties of CFLs.",
        "question": "Closure properties of CFLs means that if we applied an operator on 2 CFL languages, the result must be CFL.",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q3": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Given Given 2 CFL $L_1$, and $L_2$.",
        "question": "What do we know for certain for $L_1$ and $L_2$?",
        "answer": ["Both have CFG", "Both have PDA"],
        "choices": ["Both have CFG", "Both have PDA"]
      },
      "q4": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Given Given 2 CFG $G_1=(V_1,T_1,S_1,P_1)$ and $G_2=(V_2,T_2,S_2,P_2)$<br/> The union is also CFL. So CFL are closed under union.",
        "question": "Suppose that $G_3 = (V_3,T_3,S_3,P_3)$ is the grammar for the union between $L_1$ and $L_2$. What is $V_3$?",
        "answer": "$V_3 = V_1 \\cup V_2\\cup \\{S_3\\}$",
        "choices": ["$V_3 = V_1$", "$V_3 = V_2$", "$V_3 = V_1 \\cup V_2$", "$V_3 = V_1 \\cup V_2\\cup \\{S_3\\}$"]
      },
      "q5": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Given Given 2 CFG $G_1=(V_1,T_1,S_1,P_1)$ and $G_2=(V_2,T_2,S_2,P_2)$<br/> The union is also CFL. So CFL are closed under union.",
        "question": "Suppose that $G_3 = (V_3,T_3,S_3,P_3)$ is the grammar for the union between $L_1$ and $L_2$. What is $T_3$?",
        "answer": "$T_3 = T_1 \\cup T_2$",
        "choices": ["$T_3 = T_1$", "$T_3 = T_2$", "$T_3 = T_1 \\cup T_2$"]
      },
      "q6": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Given Given 2 CFG $G_1=(V_1,T_1,S_1,P_1)$ and $G_2=(V_2,T_2,S_2,P_2)$<br/> The union is also CFL. So CFL are closed under union.",
        "question": "Suppose that $G_3 = (V_3,T_3,S_3,P_3)$ is the grammar for the union between $L_1$ and $L_2$. What is $P_3$?",
        "answer": "$P_3 = P_1 \\cup P_2 \\cup \\{S_3 \\rightarrow S_1 | S_2 \\}$",
        "choices": ["$P_3 = P_1$", "$P_3 = P_2$", "$P_3 = P_1 \\cup P_2$", "$P_3 = P_1 \\cup P_2 \\cup \\{S_3 \\rightarrow S_1 | S_2 \\}$"]
      },
      "q7": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Given Given 2 CFG $G_1=(V_1,T_1,S_1,P_1)$ and $G_2=(V_2,T_2,S_2,P_2)$<br/> The Concatenation is also CFL. So CFL are closed under Concatenation.",
        "question": "Suppose that $G_3 = (V_3,T_3,S_3,P_3)$ is the grammar for the Concatenation between $L_1$ and $L_2$. What is $V_3$?",
        "answer": "$V_3 = V_1 \\cup V_2\\cup \\{S_3\\}$",
        "choices": ["$V_3 = V_1$", "$V_3 = V_2$", "$V_3 = V_1 \\cup V_2$", "$V_3 = V_1 \\cup V_2\\cup \\{S_3\\}$"]
      },
      "q8": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Given Given 2 CFG $G_1=(V_1,T_1,S_1,P_1)$ and $G_2=(V_2,T_2,S_2,P_2)$<br/> The Concatenation is also CFL. So CFL are closed under Concatenation.",
        "question": "Suppose that $G_3 = (V_3,T_3,S_3,P_3)$ is the grammar for the Concatenation between $L_1$ and $L_2$. What is $T_3$?",
        "answer": "$T_3 = T_1 \\cup T_2$",
        "choices": ["$T_3 = T_1$", "$T_3 = T_2$", "$T_3 = T_1 \\cup T_2$"]
      },
      "q9": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Given Given 2 CFG $G_1=(V_1,T_1,S_1,P_1)$ and $G_2=(V_2,T_2,S_2,P_2)$<br/> The Concatenation is also CFL. So CFL are closed under Concatenation.",
        "question": "Suppose that $G_3 = (V_3,T_3,S_3,P_3)$ is the grammar for the Concatenation between $L_1$ and $L_2$. What is $P_3$?",
        "answer": "$P_3 = P_1 \\cup P_2 \\cup \\{S_3 \\rightarrow S_1\\ S_2 \\}$",
        "choices": ["$P_3 = P_1$", "$P_3 = P_2$", "$P_3 = P_1 \\cup P_2$", "$P_3 = P_1 \\cup P_2 \\cup \\{S_3 \\rightarrow S_1\\ S_2 \\}$"]
      },
      "q10": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Given Given a CFG $G_1=(V_1,T_1,S_1,P_1)$<br/> The Star-Closure is also CFL. So CFL are closed under Star-Closure.",
        "question": "Suppose that $G_3 = (V_3,T_3,S_3,P_3)$ is the grammar for the Star-Closure of $L_1$. What is $V_3$?",
        "answer": "$V_3 = V_1 \\cup \\{S_3\\}$",
        "choices": ["$V_3 = V_1$", "$V_3 = V_1 \\cup \\{S_3\\}$"]
      },
      "q11": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Given Given 2 CFG $G_1=(V_1,T_1,S_1,P_1)$ and $G_2=(V_2,T_2,S_2,P_2)$<br/> The Concatenation is also CFL. So CFL are closed under Concatenation.",
        "question": "Suppose that $G_3 = (V_3,T_3,S_3,P_3)$ is the grammar for the Star-Closure of $L_1$. What is $T_3$?",
        "answer": "$T_3 = T_1$",
        "choices": ["$T_3 = T_1$", "$T_3 = T_1 \\cup \\{*\\}$"]
      },
      "q12": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Given Given 2 CFG $G_1=(V_1,T_1,S_1,P_1)$ and $G_2=(V_2,T_2,S_2,P_2)$<br/> The Concatenation is also CFL. So CFL are closed under Concatenation.",
        "question": "Suppose that $G_3 = (V_3,T_3,S_3,P_3)$ is the grammar for the Star-Closure of $L_1$. What is $P_3$?",
        "answer": "$P_3 = P_1 \\cup \\{S_3 \\rightarrow S_1\\ S_3 \\mid \\lambda\\}$",
        "choices": ["$P_3 = P_1$", "$P_3 = P_1 \\cup \\{S_3 \\rightarrow S_1\\ S_3\\}$", "$P_3 = P_1 \\cup \\{S_3 \\rightarrow S_1\\ S_3 \\mid \\lambda\\}$"]
      },
      "q14": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Theorem} CFL's are not closed under intersection and complementation",
        "question": "In case that we need to prove that something is not true, we can just provide an example that negiate the rule",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q15": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Theorem} CFL's are not closed under intersection",
        "question": "Let $L_1 = \\{a^nb^nc^m | n,m > 0\\}$ and $L_2 = \\{a^nb^mc^m | n,m> 0\\}$. Are $L_1$ and $L_2$ CFL?",
        "answer": "Yes",
        "choices": ["$L_1$ is not CFL", "$L_2$ is not CFL", "Yes"]
      },
      "q16": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Theorem} CFL's are not closed under intersection",
        "question": "Let $L_1 = \\{a^nb^nc^m | n,m > 0\\}$ and $L_2 = \\{a^nb^mc^m | n,m> 0\\}$. $L_1 \\cap L_2 = \\{a^nb^nc^n | n >0 \\}$, which is not CFL",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q17": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Theorem} CFL's are not closed under intersection",
        "question": "Let $L_1 = \\{a^nb^nc^m | n,m > 0\\}$ and $L_2 = \\{a^nb^mc^m | n,m> 0\\}$. $L_1 \\cap L_2 = \\{a^nb^nc^n | n >0 \\}$, which is not CFL. So CFL are not closed under intersection",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q18": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Theorem} CFL's are not closed under complementation",
        "question": "Using Demorgan Law, $L_1 \\cap L_2 = \\overline{\\overline{L_1} \\cup \\overline{L_2}}$, since the equation include the intersection, then the result is not CFL",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q19": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What about the intersection between regular languages and CFLs. This is called $\\textbf{regular intersection}$",
        "question": "Suppose that $L_1 = \\{a^nb^ma^n | m> 0, n>0 \\}$, and $L_2 = \\{w | w \\in{\\Sigma}^{*}$ and $w$ has an even number of b’s$}$, $\\Sigma =\\{a,b\\}$. $L_1$ is ",
        "answer": "CFL",
        "choices": ["CFL", "Regular Language"]
      },
      "q20": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What about the intersection between regular languages and CFLs. This is called $\\textbf{regular intersection}$",
        "question": "Suppose that $L_1 = \\{a^nb^ma^n | m> 0, n>0 \\}$, and $L_2 = \\{w | w \\in{\\Sigma}^{*}$ and $w$ has an even number of b’s$}$, $\\Sigma =\\{a,b\\}$. $L_2$ is ",
        "answer": "Regular Language",
        "choices": ["CFL", "Regular Language"]
      },
      "q21": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What about the intersection between regular languages and CFLs. This is called $\\textbf{regular intersection}$",
        "question": "Suppose that $L_1 = \\{a^nb^ma^n | m> 0, n>0 \\}$, and $L_2 = \\{w | w \\in{\\Sigma}^{*}$ and $w$ has an even number of b’s$}$, $\\Sigma =\\{a,b\\}$. $L_1 \\cap L_2 = \\{a^nb^mb^ma^n\\}$ is ",
        "answer": "CFL",
        "choices": ["CFL", "Regular Language"]
      }
    }
  }
}